《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
是中城的市民  他们在回复我的文章
It's the city, they're responding to my article.
这人说他两天前在第五大道和克诺路看到迪沃
This guy says he saw DeVoe on 5th and Knoll two days ago.
是的
Yeah.
这意味着迪沃无法再躲着我们了
This means DeVoe can't hide from us anymore.
思考帽注入的暗物质
The injection of dark matter from the thinking cap,
使我的神经突触过载了
which overwhelmed my synapses.
我越多地想要使用我的大脑
The more I try to use my brain,
我就会越快失去它
the sooner I'm going to lose it.
迪沃计划把他的五颗卫星
DeVoe plans to position each
分别发射到绕地球轨道的特定位置
of his five satellites around the globe.
正在计算结果
等每个卫星串联时
And when the satellite link up--
他就会用这种连接
He'll use that network
发射一系列大量暗物质
to emit a series of dark matter bursts.
会重启地球上每个
It will reboot the pre-frontal cortex
男女老幼的前额皮质
of every man, woman, and child on this earth.
我们需要零科技装置
We know we need a tech-free projectile
来阻止迪沃的卫星
to stop DeVoe's satellites.
所以我们一直在找物体
We've been looking for an object
其实我们真正需要的是人
when what we really need is a person--
阿姆内特
Amunet.
会产生巨大破坏的爆炸
It will deliver one savage concussive blow.
但机会只有一次
But you only get one shot.
最初  我们是要开启大悟之道
Initially we set out to enlighten the world.
现在你想统领它
Now you want to rule it.
我要离开你了  克利福德
I am leaving you, Clifford.
天眼会秘密行动队
狄格尔特工  很高兴见到你  长官
Agent Diggle. Good to see you, sir.
-我们已经把样品准备好了  -样品
- We have the specimen ready-- - The specimen?
那里面是一个
That's a man in there
我们应该保护的人
that we are supposed to protect.
当然  长官
Of course, sir.
我们最强大的超能力抑制器
Our most powerful meta-dampeners
在这栋楼里布置好了  我想你保证
are set on the building, I assure you.
猫王  香蕉
Elvis Banana.
亨德里克斯  意大利面
Hendrix Spaghetti.
-眼球扫瞄  -DNA样本  长官
- Eye scan? - DNA sample, sir.
去年这个时候  中城分部
Central City branch had some trouble with
在转换器上遇到了麻烦
a transmogrifier this time last year.
约翰·狄格尔
你可以进去了  长官
You're good to go, sir.
很好  关掉抑制器
Good. Now drop the dampener.
在爆炸中受了伤
Got caught in a blast.
小拳王现在被植入了芯片
Slugger's microchipped now,
抑制器会扰乱频率
Dampener scrambles the frequency.
真实身份揭露
技术部  这里是警卫
Technical, this is Castlellan.
放下吊桥
Lower the drawbridge.
启动
已关闭
谢谢  先生们
Thank you, gentlemen.
现代音乐
Modern music.
十分缺乏表现力所必须的
So lacking in the harmonic resources necessary
谐波源
for expressiveness.
十分缺乏
For profundity.
亨德尔管弦乐的定音鼓重140磅
Timpani in Handel's orchestra weighed 140 pounds,
我现在正将同样的重量施加在
the exact gravitational force that I am now exerting
你们的肺上
on your lungs.
音乐鉴赏基本守则
Music Appreciation 101.
今晚的演奏会将由你们尊敬的教授
This evening's recital will be conducted by your...
来指挥
beloved professor.
谁在那
Who goes there?
我的妻子
My wife...
对暴力很不感兴趣
cared very little for violence.
-站住  -但是我
- Stay where you are! - Me...
并不这样认为
Not so much.
朝他开火
Fire him up.
这是怎么回事
What's going on?
快
Go!
从我的脑子里出去
Get out of my mind!
快走  快走
Move, move, move!
快点  快点
Come on, come on!
快点
Come on!
上帝说  要有光
And God said, "Let there be light."
闪 电 侠
第四季
第二十二集
费里斯机场
我们监视了卡纳维拉尔角
Okay we've got eyes on Cape Canaveral,
太空探索技术公司和西昌卫星发射中心
Space X, and the Xichang Space Center.
还有黑鹰岛
And Blackhawk Island.
这些是北纬39度以南的所有发射台
That's every launch pad south of the 39th parallel.
好样的
Good man.
我们确定迪沃要
Okay, are we sure that DeVoe is gonna
在机场发射机器吗
launch the machine from an airfield?
如果他要把五颗卫星发射到
If he's shooting five satellites
同步轨道  这就是他需要的纬度
into synchronous orbit, that's the latitude he needs.
不论他是否还在为他妻子甩了他
And whether or not he's still moping around
而感到伤心  他都会重新出现的
about his wife ditching him, he's gonna resurface.
而且他马上会这样做
And he's gonna do it soon.
当他出现的时候  我跑起来  你跑起来
When he does, I whoosh. You whoosh.
她会爆炸
She bangs.
如果我能及时赶到的话
If I can get there in time.
我还是不够快
I mean, I'm still not fast enough
去到达迪沃的口袋维度
to make it to DeVoe's pocket dimension.
这就是为什么我们要分头行动
That's why we split up.
我们每人监视一个不同的发射台
Each one of us stakes out a different launch pad.
你是认真的吗
You're serious?
你看到过迪沃行动
I mean you've seen DeVoe in action.
他简直是单人版的末日军团
Yeah, the guy's a one man Legion of Doom.
那就派出超级朋友
So send the Super Friends.
但现在我们并不在最好的状态
Okay, but we're not at full super strength right now.
乔有了一个还没出生的宝宝
I mean Joe's got the baby on the way
凯特琳正在寻找冰霜杀手
and Caitlin's looking for Killer Frost.
哈里
Harry's...
这把椅子是从哪里冒出来的
This chair came out of nowhere.
艾伦  韦斯特·艾伦
So hey, Allen. West Allen.
-拉蒙  -西斯科
- Ramon. - Cisco.
西斯科·拉蒙  各位
Cisco Ramon. Guys.
看看这个
Check this out. Okay?
有人在博客上发布了关于思考者的文章
Somebody has been blogging about the Thinker.
关于迪沃和公车超能力者  所有这些
About DeVoe and the bus metas, all of it, okay.
如果找到这个博主  我们就能阻止思考者
And if we find this blogger, we can stop the Thinker.
-伙计  -伙计
- Hey, buddy. - Hey, buddy.
这是我的博客
That's--that's my blog.
看看署名
Look at the byline.
不是爱瑞丝·韦斯特·艾伦写的
It's not written by Iris West Allen, okay?
作者是一位匿名的中城市民
It's written by Anonymous Central City Citizen.
扔掉麦克风
Mic drop.
-拿好那个麦克风  -它是想像中的
- Hold on to that mic. - It's imaginary.
我让你帮我校对的  记得吗
I asked you to proofread this for me, remember?
你让我帮你校对  什么时候
You asked me to proofread this when?
今天早上吗
This morning.
就是今天早上
That's when.
你当时说  哈里  你可以校对一下
When you said, "Harry... will you proofread,
-你可以校对  -是的
- will you proofread..." - Yeah.
我们先给他找一个没有这么多椅子的房间吧
Let's start by finding him a room with less chairs.
好的  很好
Okay. Good.
地上这些是火药吗
Is that powder on the floor?
最新访客  402679
你有40万的新访问量  太不可思议了
You have 400,000 new views. That's amazing.
我知道  对吧
I know, right?
各地的人们都在这里评论
I mean, people have been writing in from all over
分享他们的想法  上报迪沃的踪迹
sharing their theories and reporting DeVoe sightings.
-还有马尔利泽的踪迹吗  -是的
- And Marlize sightings? - Yeah.
是这个女人吗
有线索请发给我们
我这几天一直在找寻她的下落
I've been trying to track her down for days.
我知道哈里认为他们分开了
I know Harry thinks that they split up,
但是她还是和迪沃一样危险
but she's still just as dangerous as DeVoe.
那我们为什么让平民去寻找她的下落
Right, so wh-- why would we send citizens after her?
我很愿意告诉人们真相  但是
I'm all for telling people the truth, but--
我是说在我说服你之后
Yeah, I mean after I convinced you.
我知道...  不知道
Yeah, I just-- I don't know.
不知道让人们帮我们做事
I don't know if it's the best idea
是不是个最好的办法
to send people out there to do our jobs for us.
不  我们鼓舞了他们  巴里
No, we're inspiring them, Barry.
我们可以告诉他们
I mean, we could be the ones to show them
如何去做好事
how to do the right thing.
我刚刚有新线索了
I just got a new lead.
博客新通知
博尔曼
辐射
Fallout...
所以你觉得你的精神失常
So you think your psychosis made
导致你的朋友消失了吗
a friend of yours disappear?
她真的是我的好朋友
Yeah, I mean, she's a really good friend of mine.
几乎就是我的一部分
Almost like a part of me.
那你的朋友
So your friend, is...
她现在和我们一起在这里吗
she with us here right now?
不  我不是精神分裂患者
Oh, no, I'm not schizophrenic, um...
她更像是另一个人格
she's more like another personality.
多重人格障碍
Dissociative identity disorder.
一般是由心理创伤所引发的
That is usually caused by trauma,
从你的过往来看  你经历过很多事
and from your history you've had quite a bit.
是的  我亲眼看到我未婚夫死去
Yeah, I did see my fiance die.
两次
Twice.
然后轮到我的男朋友变成坏人
And then my next boyfriend turned evil.
其实我指的是童年创伤
I actually meant childhood trauma.
和我说说你父亲
Tell me about your father.
我爸  他是世上最好的爸爸
My dad? He was the best.
爱我  支持我
Loving, supportive,
总是督促我变得更聪明
always pushed me to get smarter.
他过世后  你的感受如何
And how did you feel when he passed?
我...  他曾患有肌萎缩侧索硬化症
I-- He had ALS, he...
他总是对我们隐瞒他的病情
was always hiding his symptoms from us.
他不想我们看到他受苦
He never wanted us to see him suffer.
有时在我们年轻的时候
Sometimes when we're young
我们压抑那些令我们感到害怕的事
we repress things that scare us.
我没有压抑我童年的任何事
Oh, I'm not repressing anything from my childhood.
我那位失踪的朋友是几年前出现的
My missing friend just appeared a couple years ago.
是我成年的生活让我变成这样的
It's my adult life that's got me like this.
很对不起  我必须得走了
I'm so sorry. I have to go.
你是按小时收费的吗
Do you charge by the hour?
你和你的朋友
For you and your friends,
是按一刻钟收费的
the quarter-hour.
有人向我爆料了辐射的行踪
I got a tip about Fallout,
但是让基尔戈的密码给打乱了
but it's been scrambled by Kilgore's code.
现在好了  复原了
Hmm, not anymore. Consider it unscrambled.
迪沃要去抓博尔曼
迪沃
Devoe.
我们知不知道天眼会把博尔曼关在哪里吗
Where's A.R.G.U.S. keeping Borman? Do we know?
我无法锁定莱拉的位置  但我可以试试狄格
I-I can't ping Lyla, but I can try Dig.
我直接去找他好了
I'll just go get him.
垃圾桶
Trash can.
-回收桶怎么样  -不行
- How about the recycling? - Nope.
-我拿好了  -不是吧
- I got it, I got it. - Really?
刚才觉得这个很好
Seemed like a good idea at the time.
抱歉  兄弟
Sorry, man.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我们能不能...  对不起
Can we just-- I'm sorry.
我恨你  把我拽来干什么
I hate you. What is this about?
尼尔·博尔曼  我们交给你们
Neil Borman, the man we left with you,
交给天眼会的人  你们把他关在哪里
with A.R.G.U.S. where you keeping him?
巴里  那是机密信息
Barry, that's classified information.
我不是天眼会的指挥官  我...
I'm not the director of A.R.G.U.S. I--
狄格  我们没时间了
Dig, we don't have time.
告诉我吧
Please.
他在一个叫做城堡的地方
He's at a place called the Castle.
那是个荒无人烟的地方
It's a thousand miles away from anything.
拜托  你能查一下吗
Please. Can you check it?
天眼会监狱
允许进入
看来除了我  天眼会一切正常
Okay, looks like everything's fine in A.R.G.U.S. except for me.
天眼会监狱
狄格尔
约翰
所有系统访问权
上面显示我六个小时前去过那里
Says I checked in six hours ago.
迪沃可以变形
DeVoe can shapeshift.
加上融点的超能力  他能骗过DNA扫瞄仪
With Melting Point's powers, he can trick a DNA scanner
占领s整座监狱
and take over the building.
狄格尔  狄格尔  狄格尔
Hey, Diggle. Diggle, Diggle.
辐射指数达到一万  并且持续上升
10,000 rads and climbing.
博尔曼的身体情况已经很危急
Borman's body's gone critical already.
我们救不了他了
We can't save him.
如果那间牢房的辐射指数达到十万
If that chamber hits 100k,
就会开始引发核聚变
it'll start generating nuclear fusion.
-就像是太阳核聚变的核心  -无限燃料
- Like core of the sun fusion. - Infinite fuel.
他在利用博尔曼的身体做电池
He's using Borman's body as a battery.
那就是那台机器的最后一个部件
That's the last piece of the Machine.
等等  电池吗
Wait. A battery?
博尔曼密闭牢房只有304米高
Borman's containment cell is 10 feet tall.
而迪沃有能力把牢房缩小
And DeVoe has the power to shrink it down.
他会给卫星充电
He'll charge the satellites.
然后他只要把它发射出去
All he'll have to do is launch 'em.
我们有多少时间
How long do we have?
照这个融合率来看  我们有...
At this rate of fusion, we have...
十二小时  然后大悟之道就要开始了
12 hours until the Enlightenment begins.
狄格已经回到了星城
Okay, Dig's back in Star City.
我现在就去找迪沃
Now, I'm going after DeVoe.
暂时先别冲进城堡
Don't go storming the Castle just yet.
你们现在看到的是天眼会安装在大楼里的
You're looking at motion activated electro-shock plates
动作感应电击板
that A.R.G.U.S. installed in the facility.
七万伏特吗  撞到其中一个
70,000 volts? You hit one of those,
你肯定会被电晕的
you'll be knocked out for sure.
那进去的时候  我会避开电击板的
So I'll avoid them when I go in.
明智之选
Okay. Genius idea,
如果电击板不是每两小时随机转换位置的话
if their placement didn't randomize every couple hours.
所以迪沃要给他的电池充电12个小时
So DeVoe's basically charging his battery for 12 hours,
并且处于天眼会的全面保护之下
completely protected by A.R.G.U.S. defenses.
然后他有可能会跳进口袋维度
And then he'll probably just jump into a pocket dimension,
就能离开那里了
and he's out of there.
如果我不避开电击板呢
What if I don't avoid the plates?
如果我撞上去呢  撞上所有的电击板
What if I hit 'em? All of 'em.
我说真的  如果我进入闪电时间
I'm serious. I mean, if I go into Flash Time,
我就能利用每一个电击板的电流作为燃料
I could use each plate's electric current as a fuel source.
然后我就有足够快的速度
Then I'd be fast enough
跟着迪沃进入他的口袋维度了
to follow DeVoe into his pocket dimension.
你会受到巨大的冲击
You would get a serious boost.
再说一次  另一个明智之选
Again, another genius idea,
假设撞到电击板不会引发电气爆炸呢
if hitting the plates didn't cause an electrical explosion.
但是在冲击波之前
Yeah, but I'd be through the pocket dimension
我早已经穿越到口袋维度
before the blast wave,
可以炸毁另一边的卫星了
ready to blow up the satellite on the other side.
卫星有结果了
Satellite results came in.
好了
Okay.
我去
Oh, frell me.
什么  怎么了
What? What is it?
有六个电击板
We got six plates
而电击板上面有六个热能信号
and six heat signatures above them.
里边还有天眼会的特工活着呢
There are A.R.G.U.S. Agents still alive in there.
他手上有人质
He has hostages.
你可以跑过一个电磁爆炸
You can outrun an electrical explosion.
他们可不行
They can't.
他是怎么让他们悬着的
How's he keeping them suspended like that?
我想我知道怎么办到的
I think I know how.
你知道我最喜欢教学的
Do you know what my favorite thing
什么地方吗
about teaching is?
有一群着迷的听众
Having a captive audience.
我已经三天没离开这个位置了
I haven't moved from this spot in three days.
宝贝  你得抱着我去医院了
Baby, you're gonna have to carry me into the hospital.
好吧  我拿了零食
Okay, so I got snacks.
给你拿了衣服  还有宝贝的衣服
I got clothes for you. I got clothes for the baby.
该死  我忘东西了
Damn, I forgot something.
乔  我们在医院不需要武士刀
Joe, we are not gonna need a katana at the hospital.
好吧  你又钻进我脑子里了
Okay, so you're in my head again
而且我们非常有可能
and it's entirely possible that we get attacked
在医院被武士袭击
by a samurai at the hospital.
你已经重新打包过五次了
You have already repacked that bag five times.
你读了十本不同的生育指南
You've read ten different books on birthing methods.
顺便一提  我喜欢说无痛分娩那本
By the way, I love the one about Lamaze.
-但是  -该死  这孩子在哪
- Yeah, but- - Damn, where is this boy?
你已经给沃利发了一堆语音了
You have already left Wally a dozen voice mails.
他可是在货真价实的时间机器上
He's literally on a time machine,
所以他可没有借口不按时到达
so he has no excuse not to show up on time
看望他新出生的妹妹
to meet his new baby sister.
真抱歉  我只是很紧张
I'm sorry. It's just nerves.
咱们之前都经历过这些事
We've both done this before.
不会有什么意外的  好吗
Not gonna be any surprises, okay?
这可是会...
This is gonna be...
非常牛逼
totally sick.
牛逼
Sick?
你感觉不舒服吗
Are you feeling sick?
没  兄弟  没事
Nah, brah, nah.
这生产绝对会特牛逼
This delivery is gonna be sick.
生这孩子肯定会是个史诗大爆炸
Having this baby is gonna be like one epic wave.
你没事吧  你吓到我了
You okay? You're scaring me.
远着呢
Far out!
那是我定的披砸  香葱和菠萝  超棒
That's the 'za I ordered. 'Chovies and pineapple. Tubular.
超棒  兄弟
Tubular, brah!
这是你的披砸
There's your 'za!
总共是八块五
That'll totally be 8.50.
谢了  兄弟  你这房子真是
Thanks, brah. Hey, this house is--
帅  所有人都这么说
Bitchin', yeah, everybody says that.
不是  很难找
No. Hard to find.
外边那些树丛真隐蔽
Those are some gnarly bushes outside.
来啃些披砸吧  兄弟
Let's crush some 'za, brah.
老兄  老兄
Dude! Dude?
她在哪
Where is she?
什么在...
Where is--?
她在哪  我没看到她
Where is she? I don't see her.
不是  哈里  我说的是追踪马尔利泽
No, Harry, I--I'm talking about tracking down Marlize.
如果迪沃重新出现了  她或许也会
If DeVoe has popped back up then she might too.
我们需要把她送到管道监狱里
And we need to put her in the Pipelie
以免她再造成更多麻烦
before she causes any trouble.
你怎么追踪她的
How are you tracking her?
我的读者送来了上百条线索
Well, my readers have sent in hundreds of tips.
加上有面部识别
Plus there's facial recognition
-还有信用卡记录  -事实
- and credit card checks- - Facts.
-没错  -错了
- Right. - Wrong.
-什么  -你在查找事实
- What? - You're looking at facts
而你应该关注一下感觉
when you should be focusing on feelings.
你还记得"哈里森委员会"吗
You remember the Council of Harrisons?
-我记得  -帅气但烦人
- I do. - Handsome but annoying.
他们教会了我如果你想...
Well, they kind of taught me that if you wanna...
如果你想跟随迪沃的行为
if you wanna follow DeVoe's actions
你就得专注在迪沃的动机上
you gotta focus on DeVoe's motives.
基本上也就是迪沃的感觉
Which is basically DeVoe's feelings,
所以要说感觉  如果你是马尔利泽·迪沃...
and so feelings, if you're Marlize DeVoe--
你在哪里会感到安全
where are you gonna feel safe?
所以说  如果我挖掘她的过去
So if I dig into her past,
我或许就能找出她现在的位置
maybe I can figure out where she is now.
哈里  这很有帮助  谢谢你
Harry, that's really helpful. Thank you.
谢谢你  爱瑞丝·韦斯特说了这句话
Thank you, Iris West, for saying that, I...
我感觉没有之前那么有帮助了
I-I don't feel helpful that much anymore.
所以谢谢你
So thanks.
-你忙吗  哈里  -我
- Are you busy, Harry? - Me?
是啊  你
Yeah, you.
你能不能帮我一起做调查呢
Would you maybe wanna help me investigate?
-好的  -那好
- Yes. - Okay, cool.
那好
Okay, cool.
-什么时候  -我们现在就开始
- When... - We're gonna--Right now.
你们给我发警报了吗
Hey. Did you guys send an alert?
是的  我们想出了
We did. We think we've figured out
如何阻止迪沃并拯救人质的方法了
how to stop DeVoe and save the hostages.
是什么
What--what is it?
我们
Us.
你让我们和你一起进入闪电时间
You bring us into Flash Time with you.
听着各位  这真不错
Look guys, that's great, you know,
你们是想帮忙  但是如果我在天眼会里
you want to help, but we can't split up in A.R.G.U.S.
一直抓着你们  咱们就没法分开行动了
if I'm holding onto you the whole time.
调查说
Well, survey says...
你不需要那样做
you don't have to.
你们一直在研究我吗
Have you guys been researching me?
一开始我们以为在闪电时间中
At first we thought you were vibrating our molecules
你是在振动我们的分子
when we were in Flash Time,
但是那无法解释我们为什么会保持清醒
but that didn't explain why we were conscious.
于是我们就展开了头脑风暴
Which gave us this brain blast.
当你跑动时  你不仅仅进入了神速力
When you run, you don't just tap into the Speed Force.
你还在周围产生神速力
You generate Speed Force around you.
就像是你在产生闪电
It's like you're creating lightning
来保护你不受摩擦力影响
to protect you from the friction
就像是个光环
Like an aura.
所以当我带你们进入闪电时间时
So when I bring you into Flash Time
我其实是在扩展神速力光环到你们身上
I'm actually extending my Speed Force aura to you.
如果物理触碰时集中那些力量呢
And what if physical touch just focuses those powers?
我可以放手  分享我的速度
I could let go. Share my speed.
我们只能持续一小会
We'd only be able to last a few moments
之后就不行了
before we burnt out.
大概是正常时间中的55毫秒
Like 55 milliseconds of real time.
然后感谢相对论
And thanks to relativity,
这给了我们刚刚够的时间解救人质
that gives us just enough time to rescue the hostages
而你去追捕迪沃
while you chase DeVoe down the rabbit hole.
各位  我是说
Guys, I mean...
你知道我在闪电时间里看起来很正常
you know everything looks normal to me when I'm in Flash Time,
但那是我花了好几个月才熟练起来的
but it took me months to learn how to operate like that.
没错
Exactly.
这就意味着所以你来训练最合适
That's what makes you the perfect candidate for training.
训练我们
Train us.
我知道这跨步很大  巴里
I know it's a leap, Barry,
但是我们没有时间了
but we're running out of time
而且我认为这很有可能成功
and I just think it might work.
好  准备好了吗
Okay. Ready?
定时一秒钟
One second on the clock.
开始
Go.
闪电时间  我好想你
Oh, Flash Time, how I've missed thee.
开始吧
Here we go.
那闪电是不是要击中我了
Is that lightning about to hit me?
这可是你自愿的
You wanted to do this.
成功了
It's working.
谢谢你  神速力
Thank you, Speed Force.
开始
Okay, here we go.
记住  跑这么快时
Just remember, when you're moving this fast
关键不是用腿跑
it's not about running with your legs.
关键是保持冷静和专注
It's about staying calm, focused, centered.
否则你就会以3马赫的速度摔个屁股墩
Otherwise you're gonna fall on your ass at Mach 3.
好的老师  我就开个缺口
Yeah, okay, sensei, I'm just opening a breach.
你还好吗
You good?
比预料的难一点
It's a little harder than I thought.
可能我应该调整一下重心
Maybe if I shift my weight.
你已经在使用能力了
You know, you're burning up already.
你还好吗
You okay?
-我的腿动不了了  -什么
- I... I-I can't move my leg. - What?
-我动不了腿  -冷静
- My leg's not working. - All right, stay calm.
记住  专心  你的速度慢下来了
Remember, concentrate. You're slowing down.
我没法完全专心  我得保持放松
I can't really concentrate-- I-I gotta, gotta keep it loose.
我得移动  我得开缺口
I gotta keep moving, I've got to breach, I mean--
你得冷静
You gotta stay calm.
我得让腿动起来
Okay, well, I gotta get the leg to move.
但我的两条腿都卡住了
Now both of my legs are stuck.
-什么  -我的腿卡住了
- What? - My--my legs are stuck.
我的腿现在就是两根冰冻鼓槌
I'm working with two frozen drumsticks here.
-放松  -好
- Okay, just relax. - Okay.
我要摔了
Now I'm falling.
你还好吗
You okay?
还好  我的腿不听使唤  但我能掌握这个
Yep. Yep. My leg's just asleep, but I'm gonna get this.
是乔和塞西尔
It's Joe and Cecile.
我能接个电话吗
Do you think I can spare a minute?
我要散散步
Just gotta walk it off.
我们趁机歇一歇
Yeah, we could use a break.
好消息是你非常健康
Good news is you're totally healthy.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
凯特琳  别想说放松
Oh, no, Caitlin, please don't think "Relax."
要是你怀孕九个月
If you were nine months pregnant
并且忽然特别想吸大麻
and you suddenly started craving Master Kush and surf,
你也放松不了
I don't think that you would relax.
实际上  我在想松弛肽
Actually, I was thinking relaxin.
那种激素
The hormone?
你离预产期越近
As we get closer to your due date,
你的身体就会分泌更多的松弛肽来放松韧带
your body releases relaxin to loosen the ligaments
好让生产容易一点
to make it easier to deliver the baby.
你在扩张
It's like you're literally stretching.
你认为这种激素扩张了她的超能力
So you think this hormone is stretching her meta powers?
对  她现在不仅仅在读心
Yes, I think instead of just reading people's minds,
她在使用他们的大脑
she's now inhabiting them.
太棒了
Great. That's great. I mean that's just
心理咨询时又多一个谈资
one more thing for me to talk about in therapy.
你能相信芬科尔医生今早说了什么吗
I mean can you believe what Dr. Finkel said this morning?
宝贝  我们今早没见她
Babe, we didn't see her this morning.
我见了
Uh, I did.
她认为我在压抑什么东西
She thinks that I'm repressing something.
压抑什么东西
I mean, repressing something?
多疯狂啊这是  天哪
How crazy is that? Oh, my God.
这个锥型瓶上都是水渍
This Erlenmeyer flask is covered in water spots.
她肯定是我
Yeah, she's definitely me.
你要这个吗
Here why don't I give you this.
它能帮你深呼吸并且集中注意力
It'll help you take some deep breaths and focus.
我认识舒喘灵喷雾剂  谢谢你
I'm familiar with an albuterol inhaler, thank you.
天哪  我真抱歉  凯特琳
Oh, my God. Oh, oh, I'm so sorry, Caitlin.
别担心
Don't worry about it.
你就是顺着我的直觉走了
You're just going off my instincts.
我们怎么防止这种事情再次发生
How do we stop this from happening again?
你生产前都没办法
I don't think we can until you give birth.
最好的解决办法
So I think the best thing to do
就是让你一个人呆着并且用这个
is actually keep you isolated and use this.
别担心  我们能对付这个
Come on, we can handle that.
我要接着训练了
Okay. I'm gonna get back to training.
谢谢你  凯特琳
Thank you, Caitlin.
凯特琳  无论如何
Hey, Caitlin? For what it's worth,
大概20秒前我是你那时候
when I was you back there for like 20 seconds,
感觉好像你在无视什么
it seemed like you were trying to ignore something.
很要紧的什么事
Something really big.
我从这些超能力里
And if there's anything that I've learned
学会了一件事
from having these powers
那就是你不可能永远逃避
it's that you cannot hide from anything forever.
当心点  好吗
You just be careful, okay?
马尔利泽·马兰
Marlize Malan.
生于开普敦
Born in Cape Town.
开普敦  海边的夏日
Cape Town. Summers by the sea.
在葡萄园摘葡萄
Picking grapes in the vineyard.
取得了通货膨胀理论和工程学的博士学位
Got a PhD in inflationary theory and engineering.
总是埋首书间的可爱小书虫
Cute little button nose always buried in her book.
马尔利泽
2010年
真好
So nice.
在牛津大学工程学任教
Tenured as a professor of engineering at Oxford
在那里遇到克利福德·迪沃
where she met Clifford DeVoe.
遇到未来的丈夫的地方
Where she met her husband to be.
是不是很浪漫  相隔一个大洲
Isn't that romantic? A continent apart,
但他们仍然相遇  多么浪漫
yet they find each other. So romantic.
这么想还是很美妙的
I mean, it's beautiful when you think about it.
-很什么  -美  那是什么
- It's--it's--what? - Beautiful. What is that?
-你在干什么呢  -我在共情
- What are you doing? - I'm empathetic.
我在共情  委员会说要共情
I'm being empathetic-- Council says be empathetic.
我在共情
I'm empathetic. You know?
我在代入马尔利泽
I'm putting myself in Marlize's shoes.
我在想像她的处境  并且置身其中
I should see if she's got a pair of shoes, put myself in 'em.
不  哈里  这个
No, Harry. This?
这不是个爱情故事  好吗
This is not a love story, okay?
她嫁给了一个变态
She married a psychopath.
现在是变态  当时不是
Psychopath now, not then.
当时他还有感情
Back then he had feelings.
他们相爱  他有感情
They loved each other. He had feelings.
她有感情然后他
She had feelings then he--
丧失了那些感情  这就是她退出的原因
Lost the feelings, and that's why she got out.
这是她离开的原因
That's why she left.
她走了
She left.
韦斯特·艾伦
West-Allen.
我们应该策反马尔利泽
We should turn Marlize.
哈里  不  你不知道
Harry, no. I don't think you even know
-你在说什么  -我知道我说了什么
- what you're saying right now. - I know what I'm saying.
我有些时候很糟糕
I know. I have--I have bad days.
傻瓜哈里  但我今天不傻
Dumb Harry. But I'm not dumb today.
今天很好  我们应该策反马尔利泽
Today's a good day. We should turn Marlize.
马尔利泽能帮我们
Marlize can help us.
她干嘛要这么做
And why would she want to do that?
为了阻止那个变态
To stop the psychopath.
保护那个被困在怪物体内的人
Right? Protect the man trapped inside the monster.
马尔利泽能救所有人  马尔利泽是关键
Marlize can save everybody. Marlize is the key.
哈里  我们早就试过了
Harry, we've tried that already.
和萨维塔一起  你还记得吗  没用
With Savitar, remember? It didn't work.
你救赎不了怪物
You can't save monsters.
马尔利泽不是怪物
Marlize isn't a monster.
此外
And besides...
没多少时间了
the clock's ticking.
距离大悟之道大概还有十个小时
It's like ten hours before the Enlightenment.
我们还能输掉什么呢
What do we have to lose?
她用一把武士刀捅了我  哈里
She stabbed me with a katana, Harry.
我们还有命可丢呢
Our lives are what we have to lose.
要是我们死了那就谁也救不了
We can't save anyone if we're all dead.
-对  -我们得把她请来
- Right. - We're going to bring her in
然后阻止她
and we're gonna stop her
这样她就再也无法伤害任何人
so she doesn't hurt anyone ever again.
好吧
Okay.
我有一些资料在家
I left some of my files at home.
我要在家完成调查了
I'll finish my investigation there.
-我和你一起  -不  我没事  哈里
- I'm gonna come with. - No I'm fine, Harry.
-你就待在这里  好吗  -我和你一起
- You stay here, okay? - I'll come with.
-哈里  -我就待在这里
- Harry! - I'll just stay here.
就待在这里
Just stay right here.
好  记住这次保持冷静
All right, just remember to stay calm this time.
-你为什么盯着我  -我没有...
- Why are you looking at me-- - I wasn't--
你们两个人我都看
Both of you.
好  第二次
All right. Take two.
-太棒了  -漂亮
- Yes! - Nice!
-小坏蛋  -一个小小的宝宝缺口
- Brrrrat! - A little baby breach.
是的  巴里  宝宝缺口
That's right, Barry. A baby breach.
不久  她就会绽放成熟
And in time, she'll blossom into maturity,
但目前  在闪电时间里  她是...
but for now, in Flash Time, she's...
我小小的缺口
my little breachling.
好了  小凯
Okay. Cait.
冷冻枪还是不管用  和冰霜杀手一样
Cold Gun's still not working, just like Killer Frost.
我们得找到一个抵消摩擦的方式
We gotta find a way to off-set the friction.
该死
Ah, damn it.
我的腿动不了了
My leg's stuck.
保持冷静
All right, just stay calm.
注意
Hey, watch out!
爸  我的腿卡住了
Dad! My leg's stuck.
凯特琳  小心
Caitlin, watch out!
-凯特琳  -小凯
- Caitlin! - Cait!
-怎么了  -训练
- What happened? - Training.
你在空中离开了闪电时间
You came out of Flash Time in midair.
我觉得你受了脑震荡
I think you got concussed.
不过  我不是团队的医生
Then again, I'm not the team doctor.
我没觉得恶心
I mean, I don't feel nauseous.
让我吃点解热镇痛药
Just hand me some acetaminophen,
-继续回去训练  -不  等等
- and get back to training. - No, hold on.
我们得聊聊刚才的事
We have to talk about what happened.
什么意思  你就是走神了  对吧
What do you mean? You just lose focus, right?
-是  -不  是...
- Yeah. - No, it was--
我不清楚  有什么事让你的注意力分散了
I don't know. Something pulled your focus.
-不  我没事  -如果是真实情况
- No, I'm fine. - If this were the real thing,
-你可能就没命了  -我不是个负担
- you would have died. - I'm not a liability.
我明白
I know.
我是  我让你们置于险境之中
I am. I'm putting you guys in danger doing this.
我意识到你们想帮忙
I mean I-I realize you guys want to help,
但我不能再训练你们了
but I've got to stop training you.
巴里  拜托  这些人质
Barry, come on. Those hostages--
我会找到其他办法救他们
I'll find another way to save 'em.
你得让我们帮你
You have to let us help you.
在迪沃对我们做的一切之后...
I mean, after everything DeVoe did to us...
冰霜杀手
Killer Frost.
她是对的
She's right.
我们没时间了  值得冒险
We're running out of time. It's worth the risk.
我训练你们不是让你们去牺牲
I'm not training you guys just to get you killed.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
韦斯特·艾伦
West-Allen!
他当然跟着我回来了
Of course he followed me home.
韦斯特·艾伦
West-Allen!
West Allen!
-韦斯特·艾伦  -是5号门
- West-Allen! - Apartment five.
-你好呀  -5...你搬家了
- Hi. - Five--Oh, you moved.
-没有  -这...
- No. - This--
-这是4号门  -4
- This is apartment four. - Four.
-你住在5号  -是的
- You're in apartment five. - Yes.
我过来只是为告诉你  你是对的
So, look, I just came to say you were right.
我试着让自己站在马尔利泽的角度思考
Trying to put myself in Marlize's shoes,
却忘了也要站在你的角度思考
and I forgot I should also try to put myself in your shoes.
谢谢
Thanks.
你能承认自己的错误  很难得  哈里
It's very big of you to admit that you were wrong, Harry.
我不是...我不知道自己是不是错了
I'm not--I don't know if I was wrong--
你说过的  更像是我傻了
the word you said. It's more like I'm dumb.
我现在很笨
I'm dumb now.
-哈里  -怎么了
- Harry. - Yeah?
出于爱情  马尔利泽不会
Marlize is not gonna help us
帮助我们与她丈夫为敌
fight her husband out of love.
爱情  没错
Love. Exactly.
她...大悟之道不是因为爱
Look, she--look-- the Enlightenment was not
而诞生的  她一直是个活跃分子
born out of love. She's always been an activist.
牛津大学教授在爆炸中受伤
看看这个  在她遇到迪沃之前
Look at that. Even before she met DeVoe,
她致力于救助人民
she was trying to save people.
是的  她早期的论文非常乐观
Yes, her earlier papers were very optimistic.
她认为科技可以...
She thought that technology could--
-可以解放人类  -人类  对
- could liberate humanity. - Humanity. Right.
但她现在谁也不救了
But she's not saving anyone now.
不是基于你的观点
Not according to your perspective.
她的观点是什么  站在她的角度想
What about her perspective? Put yourself in her shoes.
请进
Come in, please.
站在她角度想想
You know? Just put yourself in her shoes.
-好吗  -哈里
- Okay? - Harry.
-怎么了  -脱鞋
- Yeah? - Take your shoes off.
你穿我的鞋  我就穿你的鞋
You put on my shoes, and I'll put on your shoes.
-我们都换鞋  -不
- We'll both trade shoes. - No.
不  哈里  我不想穿你的鞋子
No, Harry, I don't want to try your shoes on.
我想让你脱鞋  你在我家里
I want you take your shoes off. You're tracking mud
会留下泥印的  拜托
all through my house. Please.
对  抱歉
Oh. Right. Sorry.
这有点...
It is kind of...
-像阁楼  -这是我家  好吗
- more of a loft. - This is my home, okay?
这是我和巴里在一起后的第一个家
This is the first place that I've lived in with Barry.
让我感觉到爱意和安全
It makes me feel loved and safe,
所以我们要把它打理得漂亮
and so we are going to keep it nice and--
干净
clean.
怎么了
What? What is it?
你在想什么
What are you thinking about?
我知道马尔利泽躲在哪里了
I think I know where Marlize is hiding.
4号门
Apartment four.
不  不是4号门
No, not apartment four.
宝贝
Babe.
Babe?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我得把包准备好
I gotta get this bag ready. Uh...
有零食  有水
I got, I got snacks. I got water.
宝宝的换洗衣物
I got a change of clothes for the baby.
忘了我自己的换洗衣物
Forgot a change of clothes for me.
你是我吗
You're me?
这真是怪出了全新的水平  停下
This a whole new level of weird. Stop.
给我这个...
Give me this...
坐下
Sit down.
好
Okay...
好点了吗
Better?
你到底是谁
Who the hell are you anyway?
并没有好  我要打给凯特琳
Okay, not better. I'm calling Caitlin.
你在我家干什么
What are you doing in my house?
塞西尔  这是我们家
Cecile, this is our house.
塞西尔  你为什么一直这么叫我
Cecile? Why do you keep calling me Cecile?
我不是塞西尔
My name's not Cecile.
我是乔·韦斯特
I'm Joe West.
好  别  乔  乔
Okay don't! Joe! Joe.
乔  坐下
Joe, sit down.
坐下
Sit down.
好  我需要你做个深呼吸
Okay. I need you to take a deep breath.
用鼻子吸气  用嘴呼气
In through your nose. Out through the mouth.
闭上双眼
Close your eyes.
想像你正处在广阔美丽的海面
Imagine that you're sitting in a big, beautiful sea.
海浪在你身边翻涌不息
The waves are cresting over you, back and forth.
那些海浪  就是乔
Those waves... that's Joe.
现在抬头看
Now look up.
广阔  深沉  美丽的天空
Big, dark, beautiful sky
有一颗闪耀的星星
with one shining star.
那颗星就是你  塞西尔
That star is you, Cecile.
很好  你感觉怎么样
Great. How do you feel?
-乔  -天啊
- Joe? - Oh, God.
你让我清醒过来了  你怎么做到的
You pulled me back. How did you pull me back?
-拉玛兹  -我得
- Lamaz? - I-I had to switch
换换脑子  不过
some things up in my head, but...
我是不是疯了  因为刚才你不是...
Hey, am I crazy, because you were--
亲爱的  相信我  我能变成的
Babe, trust me. There are far worse
比这更糟糕的都有
heads I could have been stuck in.
我爱你
I love you.
你想清楚了吗
You figure it out yet?
没  我把发电机关了
No, I-I shut down the generator.
我能救下人质  但迪沃还是会逃跑
I can save the hostages, but DeVoe still gets away,
之后  你知道的
and then, you know.
其实我是说...
Actually, I meant...
你有没有想清楚
Have you figured out how come...
你是怎么钻牛角尖的
you lost your damn mind?
好吧  听着  我很抱歉  我只是
Okay. Look, I'm sorry. I'm just--
你只是想保护我们的安全
You're just trying to keep us safe.
我知道  这话从你嘴里说出来
I know. It's starting real familiar
听着可真耳熟
coming out of your mouth.
你还没准备好使用闪电时间
You're not ready to use Flash Time.
-不是这样  -如果你训练我们
- Not like that. - We will be ready
我们会准备好的
if you train us.
要掌握超级速度需要的不止十个小时
It takes more than ten hours to learn Super Speed.
好吗  你们可能死在里边
Okay? You guys could do in there.
如果你不带我们  我们还是会死
And if you don't take us, we'll die anyway.
我们的大脑会被清零  就是这样
Our brains get wiped, and that's it.
-这就是我们的世界末日  -不
- That's the end of our world. - No!
因为我的错而失去两位挚友
Losing both of my best friends and it being my fault--
这是我的世界末日
that's the end of my world.
你们或许认为值得冒险
You may think it's worth the risk,
但我自己受不了
but I couldn't live with myself.
巴里
Barry.
你不能因为他的事而不让我们参与
You cannot sideline us because of what happened to him.
好了
All right.
我不需要再多一个理疗师了
I don't need another therapist.
我们都失去过身边的人
Look we all lost somebody, okay.
但这从来都不是
But that never gives us an excuse
-疏远他人的借口  -我说别说了好吗
to shut each other out. - I said drop it, all right?
你以为你是唯一一个为拉尔夫的死
You think you're the only one who feels bad
-感到难过的人吗  -各位
- about Ralph dying? - Guys...
你知道他来铁山监狱见过我吗
You know he came to see me at Iron Heights?
他告诉我他很害怕  他提醒我他还没准备好
He told me he was afraid. He warned me he wasn't ready.
但我还是逼他上阵  我说回到队里
But I pushed him anyway. I said go back out there
做我的工作  背起我的重担
and do my job. My burden.
是我们创造了公车超能力者
We made the bus metas.
是我们给了拉尔夫超能力
We gave Ralph his powers.
你想说重担  是我开始这一切的
You wanna talk about burdens. I started this.
是我发射的火箭筒  是我开启了神速力
I shot that bazooka. I opened up the Speed Force,
我这么做可不是为了让你站在这儿
and I didn't do it so you can stand here
告诉我你又要孤身一人去拯救世界
and tell me you're going to save the world alone again.
我  我知道
I...I know that.
我也知道我们快没时间了
And I know we're running out of time and--
我光靠自己是做不到的  但...
I can't do this by myself, but--
我教过的每个人  最后的结局
Everybody I've tried to teach has ended up worse
都比我找上他们之前还糟
than when I found them.
那拉尔夫呢
And what about Ralph?
他变得更糟了吗
Was he worse?
在他没有退路  身边世界
You taught him that when his back
一点点崩塌时  你教会了他
was against the wall and the world was ending
他一直都有选择
around him he could always make the choice.
他可以选择做个英雄
Make the choice to be a hero.
我们也有权做同样的选择
We deserve that same choice.
我们只需要有人教我们怎么做
All we need is someone to show us how.
你们真的想这么做吗
You guys really want to do this?
如果我们携手并肩  这就不是重担
It's not a burden if we shoulder it together.
我们找到她了
We found her.
-你找到马尔利泽了  -应该是
- You found Marlize? - I think so.
她在英国
She's in England.
好
All right.
这是我们最后一个外推器
This is our last extrapolator.
设定坐标  它会打开缺口送你过去
You set the coordinates, it'll breach you there.
我们必须要阻止迪沃
We have to stop DeVoe.
等到你回来时...
By the time you get back...
我爱你
I love you.
-去拯救世界吧  -我爱你
- Go save the world. - I love you.
进展如何
Where're we at?
博尔曼就快到十万拉德了
Borman's almost at 100,000 rads.
好  我们得走了  来吧
All right, we got to go. Come on.
谢谢你  七号实验体
Thank you, subject seven.
现在你的火焰将点燃整个世界
Now your fire will light up the world.
四周安全  等我们进去后
Perimeter's secure. Once we're inside,
我们有不到一秒的时间
we'll have less than a second.
我会激活碎片  吸取他们的能量
I'll activate the plates, draw their charge.
-我来放下缺口宝宝  -我会保护
- I'll lay the breachlings. - And I'll protect
天眼会特工不受爆炸的伤害  就用这个
the A.R.G.U.S. Agents from the blast using this...
-射冰器  -射冰器
- ice shooter. - Ice shooter.
我非得叫它射冰器吗
Do I have to call it an ice shooter?
我觉得叫霜冻枪好听
I thought Frostbite sounded good.
朋友们  这东西靠射冰解决了
Guys, it solves the friction offset problem
摩擦补偿问题  所以就是个射冰器
by shooting ice, therefore it's an ice shooter.
-你就得叫它射冰器  -放松
- You call it an ice shooter. - Relax.
叫起来没这么难吧
It's just not that hard.
迪沃肯定在缩小博尔曼的牢房
DeVoe must be shrinking Borman's chamber.
我们做得到的
We can do this.
抓得住我就来吧
Catch me if you can.
我吸掉能量了
I've got the charge.
缺口宝宝准备好了
Breachling is go.
他冻上了
He's iced.
还有五个  记住  集中注意力
Five more to go. Remember, stay focused.
我们做到了
We did it.
"从前在那个宇宙某个
"Once upon a time in some remote corner
偏远的角落里有一颗星星
"of that universe, there was a star
那里一群聪明的野兽发明了认知"
upon which clever beasts invented knowing."
你在对我引用尼采吗
You're quoting Nietzsche at me?
你毁了一颗卫星
You destroyed a satellite.
满分  闪电小子
Top marks, quick boy.
你能再毁掉一千颗  但你还是
You can destroy a thousand more and you will still
会一步步走向"启蒙"
march closer to the Enlightenment.
我忘了尼采说的关于清除思想的话了
I forget what Nietzsche said about wiping minds.
我肯定是逃了哲学课
I must have skipped Philosophy class--
今年我什么都没教会你吗
Did I teach you nothing this year?
什么都没穿透你那厚重的头罩吗
Has nothing pierced you thick cowl?
想想吧
Think of it?
还是别想了  你最终只会
Or rather don't. You'll just end up
伤了自己  还是让我解释吧
hurting yourself, so let me explain.
一个受到启蒙的世界
A world enlightened.
一天之内  所有士兵都会放下手中的武器
Within a day, all soldiers will lay down their arms.
六个月内  所有核武器都会被解除
Every nuclear weapon will be disarmed within six months.
贫穷  饥荒  疾病  从根本上消失
Poverty, famine, disease-- eradicated.
我们会清理街头犯罪
We will clean up the streets.
人们会放下他们愚蠢的手机
People will put down their idiot phones
重新开始拥有好奇心
and become curious again,
而我会在那里教导他们
and I will be there to teach them.
我  不是你
I--not you--
来拯救这个堕落的世界
will save this godforsaken world.
不  你只是控制它
No, you'll just control it.
你想抹去自由意志
You want to take away free will.
这只不过是人类获取和平
A pittance for humanity to pay
所付的微小代价
to know peace.
但我们不再认识彼此
But we wouldn't know each other.
父母不记得自己的孩子
Parents wouldn't remember their kids.
丈夫忘记了自己的妻子
Husbands wouldn't remember their wives.
不错  你正好说到了点上
Good. You hit upon precisely the point.
情感是错误之父
Emotion is the father of all error.
头脑中的化学反应会使我们分心
Chemicals in our brain that distract us,
阻碍进步
impede progress.
最具毁灭性的  最可笑的不平衡
And the most destructive and ridiculous imbalance
就是你们这些弱者称为爱的东西
of all is that thing you feebles call love.
这是经验告诉我的  艾伦先生
I learned this from experience, Mr. Allen.
很快你也会知道的
And soon...you will too.
这里发生了什么
What happened in there?
你们都安全才最重要
All that matters is that you're all safe.
但迪沃呢  迪沃在哪
But DeVoe? Where's DeVoe?
别担心
Hey, don't worry.
-闪电侠跟着他呢  -谢谢
- Flash is on it. - Thank you.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
最初我们训练的时候
Back when we were training,
我就有这个记忆碎片
I had this fragment of a memory.
我觉得是我压制
I think it's something that I've been repressing
很久的东西  我记不清楚
for a long time. I don't remember much,
只记得我很小  我吓坏了
just that I was young and I was terrified.
凯特琳  你确定要我震波感应你吗
Caitlin, are you sure you want me to vibe you there?
可能你的大脑
I mean, maybe your brain kept this memory
封锁这段记忆是有原因的
under lock and key for a reason.
我需要知道是什么
I need to know what it was.
我能行的
I can handle it.
那集中注意力  坚持住
Then focus on it and hang on.
凯特琳
Caity!
不  凯特琳
Oh, no! Caity!
凯特琳  你还好吗
Caity, are you okay?
别动  我们会帮你的
Stay still! We're gonna get you help!
那是我  就在那
That's me. Right there.
凯特琳  宝贝  别
Caity--honey, don't!
冰霜杀手
Killer Frost.
那时她就是你的一部分
She was part of you even then.
粒子加速器那时还没爆炸
The particle accelerator hadn't exploded.
怎么可能
How is that possible?
英国  牛津
没人
Empty.
但这是他们在一起的第一个地方
But this is their first place together.
她会回来的  我能感觉到
She would come here. I can feel it.
茶壶还热着呢
The pot's still warm.
那意味着
That means...
-我们可以喝茶  -不
- We can have tea. - No!
-马尔利泽  -爱瑞丝  她不在这
- Marlize! - Iris, she's not here.
-出来  -爱瑞丝
- Come out. - Iris.
私自闯进别人家可不礼貌
It's rude to breach into a person's home uninvited.
还很危险  尤其是那人
And dangerous when that person is holding
跟你有仇还有武士刀
a grudge and a katana.
你们为什么来这里
Why are you here?
我来说
I got this.
我们来这里  马尔利泽
We're here, Marlize...
我们来这是因为你
we're here because you...
因为
because...
等下  你
Wait, uh, you...
你已经  你
You have--you--you've...
-我不能  我不能  -他表达不清
- I can't. I can't. - He can't verbalize it.
表达不清  就像我们假设过的一样
Not anymore. Just like we hypothesized
但之前没注意到
but never observed before.
你正经历大悟之道的
You're experiencing the penultimate stages
倒数第二阶段
of the Enlightenment.
你的大脑重启了
You mind is being rebooted.
很快你就会失去记忆
Soon you will be without memories,
没有感情
without relationships.
变成空白  这样克利福德
Just a blank slate so that Clifford
就能再教育你
may re-educate you.
很快我们都会和你一样
Soon we'll all be just like you.
马尔利泽  我们必须得阻止他
Marlize, we have to stop him.
你丈夫做得太过火了  我知道你明白的
Your husband has gone too far, and I think you know it,
否则你现在就和他一起了
or you'd be with him right now.
没错  我离开了我丈夫
Yes, I left my husband.
但这不能改变
But that doesn't change the fact
他是对的
that he's right.
如果有什么不同
If anything,
他的背叛也证明了他的观点
his betrayal proves his very point.
最聪明的人也会堕落
Man corrupts even the best of ideas.
悲观主义
Pessimism...
不比乐观主义更明智
isn't smarter than optimism.
生活中你能做的最勇敢的事
In this life the bravest thing you can be
就是乐观
is optimistic.
这话听着耳熟
Familiar words.
你在牛津的时候说过
You said them when you were at Oxford.
你遇到克利福德·迪沃的两周前
Two weeks before you met Clifford DeVoe.
我的演讲
I gave a speech
是关于技术和消除世界饥饿的
on technology and the elimination of world hunger.
我真的相信这能够实现
I truly believed it could be done.
他想改变你  马尔利泽
He tried to change you, Marlize.
但我认为内心深入你还是个乐观主义者
But I think deep down, you are still an optimist.
你仍然相信人性
You still believe in humanity.
我相信你
And I believe in you.
你之前问我愿意为我的丈夫
You asked me what I was willing to do
做什么
for my husband.
现在我来问你
And now I'm gonna ask you.
你愿意为这个世界做些什么
What are you willing to do for the world?
巴里击落了他的一个卫星
Barry shot down one of his satellites.
他做到了
He did--
迪沃看起来不怎么在乎
DeVoe didn't seem to care.
我尝试看能不能追踪它
I'll try and see if I can track it.
我不喜欢这个声音
I don't like that sound.
这上显示一个尖端实验室卫星已被激活
This says a Star Lab satellite's been activated.
-是迪沃  -他要用我们的卫星
- It's DeVoe. - He's using our satellite
来代替你击落的那个
to replace the one you destroyed.
你能阻止他吗
Well, can you stop him?
他在这
He's here.
您好  迪沃教授
Hello, professor DeVoe.
不不不
No, no, no.
迪沃
DeVoe!
启动大悟之道协议
Initiating Enlightenment protocol.
《圣经》旧约 创世纪 1:3
要有光
Let there be light.
《圣经》旧约 创世纪 1:4
-他启动了  -大悟之道
- He did it. - The Enlightenment.
我们要怎么办
What are we gonna do?
我不知道
I don't know.
神看到...  是好的
God saw...it was good.